<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C/C&#43;&#43; on Alexandre Jouandin</title>
    <link>/tags/c-c&#43;&#43;/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C/C&#43;&#43; on Alexandre Jouandin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Alexandre Jouandin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 19:48:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/c-c++/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Turtlebot</title>
      <link>/project/turtlebot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 19:48:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/turtlebot/</guid>
      <description>This project was done in pairs in the context of a class of Autonomous Robotics. We built SLAM-aided task planning software for ROS. The software was written in a mix of C++ and Python and ran on Kinect-enabled Turtlebots. We implemented:
 Object detection from laser data Object collision avoidance Face tracking Infrared-aided auto-docking Landmark recognition Visual localization WiFi signal localization Mapping Occupancy mapping Task planning  At the end of the project, the robot was able to carry-out a list of predefined tasks, namely undocking from its base, scouting around a building, mapping Wi-Fi hotspot locations, coming back to its starting point, and autodocking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Frenchize</title>
      <link>/project/smart-frenchize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:19:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/smart-frenchize/</guid>
      <description>A watchface for the Pebble Watch that displays useful informations like weather, now playing music, and upcoming calendar events on your wrist.
The app used a third-party iPhone App to pull data from the phone. I first drafted the design for the watch app. I then developed a logic behind the watch app behavior: it was able to switch screens or change button actions cleverly. I also used the latest features available at the time on the Pebble watch, like permanent storage to make the watch app work even without a connection to the phone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>