<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>deep-learning | Alexandre Jouandin</title>
    <link>/tags/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>deep-learning</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019 Alexandre Jouandin</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 18:23:53 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>deep-learning</title>
      <link>/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transformer Model</title>
      <link>/project/transformer-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 18:23:53 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/transformer-model/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We propose an in-depth analysis and reimplementation of the Transformer model (Vaswani et al., NIPS 2017). Its non-recurrent behavior and sole use of attention makes it an intriguing model to analyze. We perform a hyper-parameters search, as well as a memory-profiling study, both of these allowing us to successfully train and semantically evaluate the model on the IWSLT TED Translation task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://deepfrench.gitlab.io/deep-learning-project&#34;&gt;Read more on the project&#39;s website&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recon-Blind Multi Chess</title>
      <link>/project/recon-chess/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 17:00:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/recon-chess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;recon-blind-multi-chess-rbmc&#34;&gt;Recon Blind Multi-Chess (RBMC)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project was developed in groups of 2 as the final project for a Robotics class.
We developed an artificial agent to play the game of reconnaissance blind multi-chess (RBMC) by learning from self-play.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recon Blind Multi-Chess (RBMC) is a version of chess where each opponent cannot see the other&#39;s moves in real time. At the beginning of each turn, a player may &amp;ldquo;sense&amp;rdquo; a 3×3 section of the board to know the true state of that board for that moment in time, giving a glimpse of any opponent activity in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a complete comprehensive rule guide, see this link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://reconchess.readthedocs.io/en/latest/rules.html&#34;&gt;https://reconchess.readthedocs.io/en/latest/rules.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;approach&#34;&gt;Approach&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike classic chess, where possible board configurations has size ~10&lt;sup&gt;123&lt;/sup&gt;, RBMC&#39;s complexity is complicated by uncertainty in the observation of opponent&#39;s pieces and moves.
The game-tree complexity is exponentially expanded under imperfect information and can rival that of modern complex games like Go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adapting-alphazero-to-recon-chess&#34;&gt;Adapting AlphaZero to Recon-Chess&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by recent successes at DeepMind in applying Monte-Carlo Tree Search to play a number of board games given only game rules, we took the novel approach of training a Neural Network to supplement an MCTS to play an imperfect information game. We use entropy defined as the distribution of piece type at each square to greedily guide our sensing, which is then utilized to aggressively prune the MCTS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;technologies&#34;&gt;Technologies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code was written in Python 3.5, and the Deep Learning Framework in use was Keras with a Tensorflow backend.
The training of the algorithms was performed on Google Cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In AlphaZero, because the game is fully observable, only one root node is used to represent the current board state at each turn. In our case however we have to expand from multiple roots that all share the prior probability of being the current state. Our approach then tries its bets to expand on all possible states, while using information received from sensing to efficiently prune subtrees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an instance of &amp;ldquo;the snake chasing its tail&amp;rdquo;, the Neural Network has to be efficient for the MCTS to work optimally, but we also need the MCTS to perform somewhat accurately in the early epochs of training to direct the Neural Network training. In practice, we considered a number of strategies to prune our search tree, including foregoing exhaustive expansion of all root nodes during game simulation but still enforcing at the expansion step. We believe our MCTS implementation is robust enough since even with a randomly weighted Neural Network, the agent wins more games against the random agent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My main contribution was on the MCTS tree. I worked on implementing the MCTS tree from the AlphaZero paper while adapting it to our imperfect-information variant of the game.
This work covered the handling of the pre-turn sensing, as the results of the sensing are used to prune the tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also worked on adding multi-processing capabilities to the MCTS: since we&#39;re working with multiple root nodes, I was able to implement tree-parallelism as each subtree is independent of the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I worked on the training workflow. Since training on one computer was slow, I refactored the code to make it work across multiple Google Compute Engine instances that run in parallel and upload their game results to Cloud Storage. I then adjusted the training code to fetch this training data and to upload new versions of the model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TikTok Police</title>
      <link>/project/tiktok-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 12:07:06 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/tiktok-police/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After my work on fraud detection at Karos, I was interested to see if I could &lt;strong&gt;identify harassers on TikTok&lt;/strong&gt;, the popular video app.
With TikTok being this popular among teenagers, and with so little control over privacy settings, I felt this was a serious matter TikTok would need to tackle at one point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is still a work in progress, but already gave right to many interesting developments that involved many of my skills: the creation of the dataset alone led to the use of many reverse-engineering techniques, from SSL API man-in-the-middling to app reverse-engineering through de-compilation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently writing a blog post to describe this process of data creation, but below is a screen capture of the complex set-up I came up with to circumvent TikTok&#39;s counter-measures against bots:&lt;/p&gt;



  

&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;picture&gt;
&lt;source type=&#34;video/mp4&#34; srcset=&#34;/img/tik-tok-demo/anim.mp4&#34;/&gt;
&lt;source type=&#34;video/webm&#34; srcset=&#34;/img/tik-tok-demo/anim.webm&#34;/&gt;
&lt;source type=&#34;image/gif&#34; srcset=&#34;/img/tik-tok-demo/anim.gif&#34;/&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/tik-tok-demo/anim.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Sorry, your browser does not seem to support HTML5 animated images.&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/picture&gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  
  &lt;p&gt;
    The dataset creation system in action
    
    
    
  &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, I have finished cleaning the data and selecting features. I am now working on creating various models of prediction and will present the results shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stay-tuned&#34;&gt;Stay tuned!&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
