<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>machine-learning on Alexandre Jouandin</title>
    <link>/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in machine-learning on Alexandre Jouandin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Alexandre Jouandin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 12:07:06 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TikTok Police</title>
      <link>/project/tiktok-police/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 12:07:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tiktok-police/</guid>
      <description>After my work on fraud detection at Karos, I was interested to see if I could identify harassers on TikTok, the popular video app. With TikTok being this popular among teenagers, and with so little control over privacy settings, I felt this was a serious matter TikTok would need to tackle at one point.
This project is still a work in progress, but already gave right to many interesting developments that involved many of my skills: the creation of the dataset alone led to the use of many reverse-engineering techniques, from SSL API man-in-the-middling to app reverse-engineering through de-compilation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrimp in Petri Dishes</title>
      <link>/project/shrimp-in-petri-dishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 19:48:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/shrimp-in-petri-dishes/</guid>
      <description>In collaboration with faculty at Université de Lorraine, this project focused on the visual tracking of freshwater shrimp (Gammarus) in Petri dishes and used indicators about their movement to quantify the water quality (roughly, the more polluted the water, the less the shrimps will move).
    Sample output of the resulting algorithm   The goal of the project was the implementation of individual shrimp tracking using image processing with minimal user involvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turtlebot</title>
      <link>/project/turtlebot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 19:48:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/turtlebot/</guid>
      <description>This project was done in pairs in the context of a class of Autonomous Robotics. We built SLAM-aided task planning software for ROS. The software was written in a mix of C++ and Python and ran on Kinect-enabled Turtlebots. We implemented:
 Object detection from laser data Object collision avoidance Face tracking Infrared-aided auto-docking Landmark recognition Visual localization WiFi signal localization Mapping Occupancy mapping Task planning  At the end of the project, the robot was able to carry-out a list of predefined tasks, namely undocking from its base, scouting around a building, mapping Wi-Fi hotspot locations, coming back to its starting point, and autodocking.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>